How could something like this be of
benefit to you?
But first of all,
without me even saying anything,
just think about this.
You can copy this by doing live streams
for
your demographic. Now, I think
that YouTube is the best place.
I kind of made my name doing them on
Facebook, but YouTube, I can share the
link before we go live.
You could also maybe even say to people,
"Hey, guys,
join my email list, and before I go live,
I will email you that link." So
then you can almost use these as a form of
squeeze, a form of getting
someone's contact information.
The best bet as well is that
once we finish this live,
it will stay on the live section on
YouTube, but then I can
copy that and I can duplicate it onto my
main video site, and I
can shave the first 90 seconds off so
that we can initiate with a
hook,
and you can already have pre-populated
questions here,
like we have here. Now, another thing
that I haven't even shared
publicly that I've been using is there
is a website called Opus Pro,
and it
clips videos for you. So
if I'm a guest on a podcast,
rather than me
being like, "Oh, hey, guys,
can you send me the footage?
Can you get me across all the files so I
can do my own clips?"
Take a YouTube URL, chuck it in,
an AI within about three minutes gives you
clips, and you can edit them,
and it ranks them on their flow, the hook,
maybe set up, and that costs like
$15
a month.
So there's a real hack there at the moment
for making long-form content.
If you look at the James Smith Business
Instagram page, I'm
basically putting the majority of my focus
on the long form.
Then I chuck the YouTube URL into that,
and it'll just clip it up and give you
clips that you can use.
So now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to jump into your
questions. So
any questions you have, I'm here
subservient to your needs.
Kevin: "How do we build our brand?" Okay.
First of all,
let's just look at what brand is.
To me, brand is who you are
and your business and
merging them together,
where brand meets personality.
So you obviously want to--
the majority of your business
is solving people's problems,
helping them feel
subtle emotions, whether it's empowerment,
confidence, whatever it is.
But then there needs to be your own
personal twist on that.
Like if you wanted to be a Michelin star
chef or a world-renowned chef,
it's not good enough to just make a good
cheeseburger.
You need to make
that cheeseburger your own,
and that's really where it is.
Now, if there's too much personality
and not enough professionalism,
you just have a vlog.
If there's too much professionalism
and not enough personality,
then you could just be a bit boring.
So it takes time,
but that's how you do it. "Hi, James.
Why do you not like a money-back
guarantee?" I love money-back guarantee.
I did a video on that.
I love a money-back guarantee because it
gives you the
confidence to really hammer
home your sales process. And also,
the biggest thing that the benefit
of offering a money-back guarantee is
that I don't have to do sales calls.
"Thoughts of mic in shot versus mic out of
shot." Here I'm using a Shure
SM7B.
So for this one,
I don't really care too much.
I actually think that some people,
when they absorb content,
they like being able
to see the mic.
In some content recently,
I've been hiding my lavaliers.
And here's another interesting one.
You know KSI? Have you ever noticed
that when KSI does videos,
he has headphones on where maybe he's
listening to his own
voice back through his head,
but there's no reason for him to wear
headphones
whilst recording YouTube videos.
Maybe if he's reacting to a video,
but he has them on all the time.
And I think it's because he wants to
look like a streamer.
And sometimes the look people have.
Sometimes people have the microphone in
there.
Some people have the lavalier in their
hand.
They're going for an intentional look with
it.
Again, why some people, including KSI,
literally have made tens of
millions of pounds
and still film from their bedroom because
they still want their
young audience to feel that, "Oh,
I could stream from my bedroom
and accomplish the
same thing." But back to your point,
I think the biggest priority has to be
quality of sound. Now, for a Shure SM7B,
there's two distances you want.
With this pop cover or a kind of
like a dead cat,
you're supposed to be one chakra away.
So I'm a little bit close to it, but
if you put the Chris Williamson fat head
on it,
you're supposed to be quite a bit closer.
But yeah, if I took this out of shot,
it could be at the detriment to my audio
quality. So, [sniffs]
yeah. All right. Who we got next? Brent.
What's up, my guy?
Hope you're still pumping, man.
You've had that one reel go above 1,000
views.
I want to see the next one as quick as
possible.
Bury:
"Any update on how to join the Discord?"
Okay.
Having some troubles with the link on the
portal. Email me if you want.
I'm going to give you my email address
here.
And to be fair,
if any of you have even got just any
questions about the program or
whatever, I'll give you my
academy one.
I'll just send it to the team
and get you invited in.
"What's up, James?
I have two in one question.
Do you plan to visit Brazil anytime soon?
And what about Neutonic in Brazil?" It's
not a territory that I think we're
looking to get into just because we
haven't got that much of a presence there.
Hmm.
But you know what? This sounds really bad.
I've had loads of places on my bucket list
growing up, but I just don't know if
South America's on there. Maybe one day.
Okay.
"What is the best way to win over new
clients or even soft approach them to get
them on board for your services?
For example, website designs, paid ads."
Okay.
So gone through a bit of this in the
content, but this is the way I like
to do it. And I'm not saying my way
is best, I'm sharing this
is the best way to do
it.
I like a four-stage approach to win people
over to do business.
Number one, socials, awareness,
problem-solving.
Right now,
what I am doing in this video
is stage one.
For some of you, including yourself,
I can tell maybe you haven't watched
that many
of my videos.
You might be relatively new here,
and you might not know too much
about my product or offering.
If I just say, "Hey,
join my business mentorship,"
I'm really discrediting
and doing a disservice to the stages
beforehand.
So this video,
I would say you're probably like a
relatively cold lead,
and by me helping you
and explaining this for maybe two minutes,
I get to make you
that little bit warmer.
Are you warm enough
that you're going to end up doing
business with me? Maybe not. But
if I can take you to stage two,
that's my job done
for today. Now,
stage two would be some kind of value
exchange in exchange for your email
address or contact
information. So for instance,
in the majority of my videos,
the call to action is,
"Hey,
at the bottom there's a link where you can
get 30 ways in 30 days." Now, for
me, that's another value add where I say,
"Look, over 30 days, I'll email you every
day to give you a bit of business advice."
Chances are that's going to nurture you,
that's going to heat you up,
it's going to warm you up over time.
And then the majority of people end up
joining my paid program between day 19
and 21.
Sometimes it's not even
that the emails are that great.
Sometimes it's that they're seeing
something work.
So for instance, there
are some people watching this live stream
right now who are
thinking, "Wow,
I'm getting to connect with James in real
time, and that's giving
me a different emotion than
if I just watched one of his very
polished, well-edited
videos. Therefore,
maybe I should put something into my own
business
that makes people realize they can come on
and have my time, or whatever."
So
sometimes seeing what I'm doing
is actually benefiting you anyway.
So if you join the email list at stage
two, then suddenly you're going, "Jesus
Christ,
although maybe I don't think this email
today was amazing, the
fact that they come in at the same time
every day is really amazing, and I could
apply this to my business." So then
suddenly we're getting into a realm where
you're starting to see what I'm using,
and that's actually warming you up without
even knowing about it,
because you're thinking, "Wow,
what James is using here to
get me is very different to what other
people are doing.
Maybe if I join his program," whatever.
Okay, so that's stage two.
Stage three would be having call to
actions in those sequences to let people
know
that there's a landing page.
And a landing page
is just simply a webpage that has
all the information you need to know.
If you go to my website,
it's very difficult for you to leave
without knowing how much it is,
what you get,
what it costs, why you should trust me,
what my clients say, all of these things.
And that should be like a menu.
We do have an option for a sales call,
but I just pay someone to take the sales
call and give them 10% of the deal,
just because some people do need that.
But the majority of people don't.
I'd say maybe like 87 to
89% of people
don't need a sales call. Why?
Because of the objection handle on the
landing page.
Then
it becomes a traffic thing, right?
Out of this, let's say 100 people
are watching me live. Cool.
How many are going to join the email list?
Let's say 25. Cool.
Out of those, how many people
are going to read all the emails?
Probably 13.
Then out of the 13, probably six
are going to get to the landing page
and feel
compelled. Cool. So that
is six new clients. Cool.
Well done. So that means
if I want to get 60 new clients,
I would just need to make
sure that I get this in front of 1,000
people.
Now, here's another statistic for you.
The amount of people
that will watch your live stream
is usually about a tenth of
the total amount of viewers
that you will get.
And if you get sign-ups for a video like
this, usually only 10% of people arrive.
But if you do sign-ups,
you can also email everyone an offer.
So for instance, when we run webinars,
we do paid ads to sign
up people to the webinar for the
awareness,
and you can run paid ads to people that
have watched your content, follow you,
but also you can also do, say-- This is a
really long answer.
You can do a lookalike audience.
So something that's really pumping in our
business at the moment is
through our paid ads,
we're starting to identify who's doing
business with us, and
we can now advertise to people
that look like that
and have the same habits.
But you can't really get
that unless you have a good organic base.
So my last bit of advice for you would be
make sure you master organic
before you do paid.
That took way too long to answer,
but it's all right.
I've got a fridge full of Nutella behind
me.
Is fitness instructing a good start for
building experience and clientele before
going self-employed? It is,
but you just won't get paid that well.
Fitness instructing can be good to
establish yourself in the gym.
And here's another thing
that I would say to this is
when you're a fitness
instructor and there's not a lot of
pressure on you,
you're employed for the gym,
and maybe it might take you two
or three months to become the man.
And what I mean by that is,
and this isn't sexist,
have you ever noticed that,
like, when people work in a restaurant,
they're in their setting.
They know everyone, they know the chef,
they know the room, they know even where
the tiles are uneven on the floor.
And you become very comfortable in that,
and
that can sometimes become quite
irresistible to people.
And personal trainers
that have been PTing in the same facility
a while become the
man or the woman.
A bit like the waitress in the restaurant
that's having a giggle
with people becomes the woman.
And it becomes almost, like, kind of sexy.
You're like, "Wow,
this person's so comfortable." So if you
become a gym instructor in a gym,
you might become incredibly comfortable in
that
surroundings, that
when you do eventually become a PT,
you're like, "Yo, what
up? Hey, Trish,
you have a good day?" You know, like, "Oi,
Dave, make sure
you know,
don't let anybody train on the leg press
again." Whatever it is.
So that can be a benefit.
The only issue is one day you're going to
go
from minimum wage to charging £35 an hour,
and sometimes
people go, "Oh, but you
were wiping down the machine last month.
Now you want me to pay you all my life
savings." It can be difficult.
Pros and cons to both.
Worked with mentored musicians before.
I'm doing music production coaching
and your shit is elite.
Thank you very much.
I haven't. Tell me your problems,
I'll see if I have an answer.
Catherine, congrats on the new motor.
Thank you.
I just want to go out
and drive it every morning.
But do you know what I'm going to drive
before?
Leads to my product because it's Black
Friday, 50% off.
Actually, that's a point.
I should probably pin a link.
Now,
me promoting my Black Friday offer goes
against much of what I just said
before.
Because here I'm sending you straight to
the landing page.
I'm sending you straight to stage three.
But the only reason
that I think you might potentially
overlook stage two is
because of the discount, it being 50% off.
So, you know,
that would be it. Wow,
I missed some of these. I'm sorry.
How would you build an advertising agency
offer?
I don't really know what that means,
if I'm honest.
Okay. Congrats.
How would you build an advertising...
Yeah, I don't know what that means.
Use Lopez is great. Hey, James.
Wanted to say I'm grateful for the videos
you're putting out. Thank you very much.
How much a year did you make being a
one-on-one PT at its peak?
Probably about £80,000, I would say,
because I lied
once getting a phone.
Then my online definitely
did way more. Online, I
was doing about £3,500 a week before I
started the
academy.
So I took a bit of a pay cut,
but I got my life back, which was nice.
Liam: "Fell off posting content.
Feel a bit lost at getting new clients for
what
I'm doing.
Tips on how I can give myself a kick in
the ass and gear again.
Feel a bit lost." Okay.
What does a client look like for you?
Are we talking online, in person?
Help me understand this.
Wait,
can you not fucking post your questions
twice. I'm getting through them.
I will fucking fight you.
I've had caffeine. I'm ready to go.
Brent:
"How to get your first online client?" The
most classic ad I see.
Keep pumping, as you might say.
Yeah. First time.
Whenever anyone's struggling to get
clients, often that's
stage four. Stage three is lacking,
stage two is lacking, and stage one
is lacking.
There's no one that's got a massive email
list that's pumping people to a good
landing page that's not getting them.
Yusef: "Do you schedule your content?" No.
I only decided I was doing this video
when I was on a dog walk just then.
"Why are you now rocking the Crocodile
Hunter mullet?" Because I am going bald.
[chuckles] That's why.
I'm going thin on top.
I've got two, three years of haircut...
No, I got two,
three months of haircuts left, mate.
I'm enjoying it while I can.
Shez:
"Can I directly link YouTube audience to
my course rather than sending them
an email?
Because I feel the email chain may get
annoying for the customer." Well,
why don't you make the fucking email chain
good then? Right?
You're like, "Oh,
they're not going to like the email list
because it's not very
good." I'm like, "Well,
fucking make it better." Because, mate,
if you can't make
an email chain good, your course
is fucked anyway. You know what I mean?
So you're there like, "Oh,
I can't even put some good emails
together, and you want
me to part money with you?" Every single
part of your system should be
as good as you can.
And you feel like you're annoying the
customer.
Listen, if you're giving someone value,
it's impossible to annoy them.
Actually, maybe that's not true. But
ultimately, if your emails
are annoying someone,
I very much doubt they're slipping off the
edge of the seat to fucking buy your
stuff.
"Are tags important in YouTube
description?" I don't really know,
if I'm honest. Some people yes,
some people no.
I use a website called Rapid Tags,
and I populate it just because it's 10
seconds
of work.
"Is working for the gym better for an
aspiring PT to build experience and
clientele before going self-employed?"
Kind of covered that before.
Can be, but
don't get bum deals. Because
if you want to quit personal training,
do too many
hours for not enough money.
"My DJ mic always moves even with the
magnet on it. Such a pain.
Do you use tape for it?"
I sometimes use tape with a lavalier,
but not for the magnet.
So maybe get a lavalier. But usually,
the magnet should have it pretty solid.
"Bought your short-form course,
nudged it into actions.
What would the mentorship course give me
versus this?
I'm not coach PT, but Willis
and probate lawyer
and love learning from you." Okay,
Jane. So in essence,
the short form content
is just very much focused on stage
one.
We don't go into too much detail about
getting people's contact information or
what a landing page looks like.
But I'd say the best value probably is the
Discord.
We have so many different threads in the
Discord, and I empty those as a
priority. Now,
that's what I would say the main thing is.
But what I would say is,
I'm going to take a mental picture of your
name.
[lip smack] So how about this?
Join today so you can pay less.
Because you're in a bit of a niche, weird
side tangent,
I'll offer you a money-back guarantee.
Now, I was offering a money-back guarantee
very openly on the course
when we launched,
but some people started taking
the piss. And what I mean by that
is people were joining.
One person copied the whole course,
then asked for a refund,
and then I went to his website
and he'd literally copied all my emails
word for
word, and then he'd
all the promises, whatever.
He pretty much just copied the course.
And I was like, you know what?
I refunded him, but I was like,
"You're a prick."
But then there was another person who kind
of did two modules and was like, "I want
my money back." And I was like... Look,
I went to their page.
They're a personal trainer.
They weren't posting content.
They just thought it was too hard.
So I took the legit money-back guarantee
down. We do have a policy in place,
but there were too many piss takers.
Anyway,
so I'm going to offer you one because
you're a lawyer.
[clears throat] To anyone else,
this is the thing, right? This
is where my gripe is with this.
This is where I'm going to be hypocritical
with it.
There are some people
that still come through for a money-back
guarantee, and 9 out
of 10 times, it's just
that they've seen the amount of work
that's there and they
don't want to do it. That's it.
They just don't want to do it.
And I go back to them, I go, "Look,
what's better for you?
Getting your money back
or working with me to make the problem go
away?" And I've
openly said this.
For some of you that join,
you might think that the course
is too basic or too
complex or whatever.
But if you communicate with me,
I will make it perfect.
So let's say you join and you go,
"This course is far too complex.
I need to understand the basics." I go,
"Let me know what that is.
I will build the basics for you."
Alternatively,
if you come to the course and you
go, "Oh,
I think I'm a bit advanced for this," I
go, "What do you need help with?"
And I'll build it for you. Because even
if there was one person that wanted to
know how to learn how to do color grading
on DaVinci Resolve, I
got someone in and we recorded the module.
So that's why I would say it's really
important that you work with me so I can
work
with you. Some people just get in,
they get buyer's remorse,
and they want to leave
and they panic. But ultimately,
I want to make this the best resource
online so you
don't fucking waste your money with other
people online.
There are some people out there.
Let's look at it now.
It's currently up for 999 US, which
is like £800.
There are people out there charging
£8,000, £10,000, £15,000,
£20,000. For what?
And I tell you what,
whilst we got people on the live,
let me tell you this.
I'm going off script.
The car I bought yesterday
or the day before, the Porsche GT3,
I didn't buy that with personal training
money.
I didn't buy it with...
Everyone in here is B2C.
You're business to consumer, most of you.
Business to consumer.
I didn't make really good money. Well,
I did make really good money, but I didn't
make fuck you money from that.
And so many business gurus in my
position, they buy the Porsche
and they go, "You can be wealthy like
me."
And it's not true.
I actually have had so much success with
this course that I
bought the Porsche.
But then so many people
are not transparent about that.
When it comes to building a business
that I'm going to teach you how to build,
is
it going to get you a Lamborghini? Maybe,
maybe not. Probably not.
My personal training business for me has
paid me a very healthy salary
for nearly 10 years.
And I think it's really important I get
that across.
I'm not going to teach you how to cheat
the ads system and how to get a
10 times ROAS on your paid ads.
I'm going to teach you how to put a
sensible
business together
that has a strong sales process to it,
that can give you a salary
that can support you long-term.
If I'm completely honest with you,
my salary from my coaching app is give
or take about
£1,500 a week after tax,
and we've been on that for eight years
and it's been great
because it's permitted me to do other
things that have
made more money, like the books,
like the drink, like this course
or whatever.
I think it's really important I get
that kind of off my back that
for most of you here,
if you can just stop listening to these
bellends
online and only listen to me
and give me your money.
So many people are like,
"Give me £25,000 and I'm going to teach
you how to make
millions." This isn't what we should all
be looking for.
We should be looking for a stress-free
sales process that's genuine,
that can play
into a brand, that doesn't require
or lean heavily on paid ads.
And then for so many of you,
it may be like three, four years' time,
if you
build a strong brand
and you do the things I teach you,
other opportunities are
going to come along
and that's probably where you're going to
get your Porsche
money.
If your profile explodes to several
hundred
thousand followers,
even in the fitness niche,
you're going to get a book offer,
and then you can use the book to get
people in your program.
You can use the program to get people to
buy your book.
There is a fucking data capture
in Not A Diet Book.
There's still people...
So I've got Harper Collins promoting my
book because they make money on it,
so then
people then sign up to my calorie
calculator from it.
So what I'm saying
is you can really diversify your offering
with so many things.
But yeah, I thought it
was important to say
that like so many people are like, "Oh,
you can get this if you do this." Nah,
and you shouldn't want the Porsche.
What you should want
is a steady salary for eight years.
Not many fitness businesses.
I would say I've not made the most out of
other people in the fitness industry,
but I've been consistent.
Trying to stay relevant for eight years.
I'm tired. That's why my hairline's going.
Okay.
"I've recently made a decision to
transition from a gaming channel to a
separate game development one.
I'm in game development in real life.
Feel like it aligns better with using
YouTube for business. Any tips?" Yeah.
So look at this. Look at me as an example,
right?
It's always best to remain as close to
your avatar as possible.
So you want to be the person in your
brand.
Now,
the majority of people I work with for fat
loss were women, so I've never
really been a woman. But the reason
that I love this
business so much more is
I kind of fell away from coaching a little
bit because I wasn't coaching anymore.
And really, for the last eight years,
all I've done is digital marketing, social
media, email marketing, all of these.
So the things I teach you now
is what I do.
It's very difficult to change who you are
without changing your offering. So, yeah.
[clears throat] Even
if it means a little bit less money,
if it means you have a
little bit more lead in your pencil,
a little bit more
va-va-voom when you wake up, 100% do it.
Okay, let's go. "Love the Nutonic.
How's the business going?
Any future steps?" Yeah.
Nutonic's going great. So the business
is expanding.
It's doing really well.
So for instance, right, this is what
year one success is going to look like for
me.
I could get my director's loan back.
So,
I invested hundreds of thousands of pounds
into Nutonic when we
launched. So if it flopped,
that's just me,
hundreds of thousands down the drain.
So this year we've been pretty profitable,
but then we
reinvest that profit into producing more
stock.
But should we get even more profitable,
we could look to potentially return the
money that we initially invested,
which kind of eradicates a little bit of
risk.
That would be nice because I've written
off that money as cost.
When it comes back to my bank account as a
director's loan,
I'll be like, "Wow.
[chuckles] I'm rich." So yeah,
that would be nice because it would
de-stress the whole project, but it's very
exciting. Yes.
Okay, Lewis.
"Where else to advertise as online PT
other than social media?"
Well,
you're not advertising as an online PT,
mate. You know what I mean?
All right. Look, let me gun you a bit,
Lewis Gunn. You are not an online PT.
You are fucking Lewis Gunn. You
are the Gunn. You're Lewis.
You should not be advertising.
You should be making Lewis well-known.
And do you know how Lewis
is going to get well-known?
Because he's going to solve every fucking
problem that you have, and he's going to
do it every day.
He's going to turn up tenaciously.
He's going to make great content.
You're going to think, "This Lewis guy
is insane
for putting out so much helpful content."
You don't advertise online
PT, mate. Because guess what?
No one wants online PT.
But do you know what they might want?
Lewis fucking Gunn.
As long as you turn up,
as long as you do the work,
as long as you build the brand,
as long as you make the offering,
as long as you understand your avatar,
you are not selling Lewis Gunn. You
are selling yourself,
brother. You know what I mean?
The whole fact that you think
that you just need to
sell online,
try and fucking get the Google ad
fucking...
You're not going to get it, mate.
You're not going to get it, brother.
So yeah, you need to flip this.
You need to turn yourself into
a brand and sell yourself. Luke.
"Just cost me 470
quid for a locksmith. How do you make
that 10 out of 10 email like the famous
laundry email?" Okay,
so you just talk about the implications of
maybe one small mistake.
You get locked out. Easy to do.
You could then maybe go to war with the
status quo.
You could be like, "Why is it in 2024
when Elon Musk
is landing rockets from space,
we're still using a funny shaped piece of
metal to open a door?
How have we come this far?
Even at university
in 2014, 10 years ago,
you got to punch a code into a door.
How have we gone backwards in
civilization?
How is something so archaic
and inefficient like a key and a lock
still the norm for so many people?" It's
crazy.
But you know what else
is equally as crazy as this?
The fact that people still think
that they can write their own
program,
or they can still lose fat without doing
this one thing that I
promote. You know what I mean?
That's the angle I'd go with. Sorry.
That's off the cuff, mate.
And
you could be like, "For the same cost,
it got me to come in my front door.
You can use me for X amount of time."
My locksmith didn't give me a money-back
guarantee, but I will.
Fucking love this. Again,
my business mentorship is currently 50%
off. I'll pin the link up. Curtis:
"What would you say
is the best way to start
scale in the drinks market?
I set up a coffee company as a volunteer
football coach
and want to use 5% of the profits to give
back to support kids.
Loving your content too.
Thanks for your time." Okay.
It's just difficult because you think this
drinks brand is incredibly difficult to
emerge without Chris and I. And
Chris and I have spent a long time
building an organic social media following
where
hopefully people can trust us. Hopefully,
people
can like us.
Hopefully, yeah,
we can get into a position
that we could leverage
that. So without that,
it's very difficult.
Sorry, Brian.
Because in essence, if you just go, "Hey,
I've got a coffee company that I want to
start up," there's no work that's been
done behind the scenes to build that
up. That's why I think
that maybe sometimes you do need to build
your brand first,
if you can.
You may just be able to get away with paid
ads, but then with a coffee
company,
it's quite hard to be a differentiator,
unless you go with something wild
like,
"Our coffee is so good
that we will send you the first bag for
absolutely free.
All you got to do is give us your email
address and your phone number."
So yeah.
That's what I would do.
I'm actually thinking of maybe bringing
out a type of
supplement business,
and that's what I'd do.
I'd say, "Hey, right,
I'm going to get quarter of a million
dollars, park it here,
and I'm going to give away quarter of a
million dollars worth of free products."
Because if the product is that good,
people will buy it.
And then you also have everyone's data.
So then maybe you've just paid £10 for
someone's email address.
And if you get a product
that someone repeat purchases,
you might not make your money back for
three orders,
but if the product's good enough,
you'll get it. Okay.
"Love your recent content.
How to offer 100% money-back guarantee
when there's hard costs for the service
you
provide. Planting trees on their land."
Okay. Maybe let's just try this out, okay?
So
[chuckles]
I would say faith in humanity, okay?
The majority of people aren't shit bags.
Maybe for the time of December, you say,
"Hey, I'm going to offer
this for free. Money-back guarantee."
And let's look at how many people
actually take you up on that. Now,
there's going to be a certain percentage
of
refunds that are completely acceptable to
the business.
Like Amazon,
even if 5% of people dishonestly ask for
their money back on their products
that never came,
they're fine because of the
profit margins from the people that don't.
So maybe it could look like...
Yeah.
Maybe it could look like that. Brian.
"Bro, you're apparently a PT
and look like you've never trained a day
in your life.
Why is it the guys in the gym look way
better than the trainers?" Okay.
Brian, first thing is,
I can tell you're semi-brain dead or
retarded because you don't even
differentiate you're between you are.
So you've said you're
when you meant you are.
So your lack of attention to detail,
even with a rip, not knowing
basic grammar, just shows me
that you're probably, yeah,
mentally retarded.
Now, second thing. I would welcome
you, bro.
We can go to the gym.
We could do bench, dead, squat,
even maybe body
weight chin-ups,
and then we do a round of jujitsu.
Now we can see.
Or even something else that I don't do,
like boxing.
And I'm more than happy to make this a
YouTube video.
My email address is here.
I've already got a title in my head.
Random hater with shit grammar
says I'm out of shape.
Whatever. And we can go, bro.
You can bring it.
Oh, what's that? Occupational hazard.
I've probably got bigger arms than you.
You know what I mean?
But I'm happy to make a video out of it,
Brian.
Also, here's another thing.
Being a personal trainer isn't about how
you look. Sure, it helps, right?
But
it's about the client.
If Susan wants to come in,
follow a non-intimidating program.
If Susan just wants to come to the gym so
she's not drinking the night before, I
don't need a six-pack for that.
But
let me tell you this, Brian,
there is a very fine line between jealousy
and inspiration.
I can tell you this.
I've suffered this myself.
And
when you look at maybe what I've done,
it's very easy for you to come to the
conclusion that I'm a dickhead,
you don't like me or whatever.
But you were so close to being inspired by
it.
So close.
And it's quite sad, if I'm honest,
because if you'd only
maybe seen what I'd done and gone, "Wow,
maybe I don't need to look like a physique
bodybuilder to take care of my family,
have a good life,
lay down on planes." You could've made
something better of
yourself, but instead you became a hater.
And do you know what?
I don't even get angry, I get sad.
I'm like,
that's just one more loser that's sat
here watching my video on a fucking,
what is it?
Sunday evening in the UK.
And instead of making your life better,
you're making my life better by giving me
things to talk about.
"What advice would you give a coach to go
from naught to 1K a month?" Still, this
is quite a blind question. Again,
what I spoke about, about stage one, two,
three,
four, I think that is pretty much massive.
The acquisition of one client shouldn't be
that hard.
And even if you don't have any social
media,
even if you didn't have a smartphone,
you should be able to walk the floor,
prospect, talk to people.
Scott:
"How pivotal do you think leaving the UK
was in terms of mindset and
business growth?" Probably quite big,
because I moved far away from my security
blanket, being my parents, my family,
and the gym I worked in.
I literally went to the other end of the
world, and if I didn't make something
of myself, I'd have to move back home.
Patrick: "What would you say
is the best way to monetize as an artist?
What would your approach be for a
service-based artist?
I create 3D animations."
3D animations. Oh.
I don't really know what that means,
if I'm honest. What is a 3D animation?
I know it's a three-dimensional animation,
but I just don't know what that is.
"Do you have suggestions on promoting
services where you cannot reach your
clients
versus social media? For example,
I'm building a property management
software,
and I think social media might not be so
good." I don't know what property
management software does.
Can you help me understand that?
So like I say, I'm not that smart.
I don't understand half this shit.
"Is your business courses only helpful
becoming a PT coach, or other businesses
work too?" No, it works for a selection.
Well,
it works for everyone because really what
I use for personal training
businesses is the same as what I'd use for
anything.
If you were selling pottery,
I would still have the four-stage sales
system.
So yeah, I think it does. "What
is your approach
when people ask you for training
prices via DM?" They don't want to know
your prices, they just want to get an
indication.
They just want more information, really.
I'd send them to a landing page. I'd go,
"Hey, if you really want to understand
what I do and how it works, go here."
And then your prices would be on there,
but
there'd be a lot more. Like this
is what it is, this is what you get,
this is why
you need it,
this is why you should trust me, this
is how you pay.
They're kind of just saying they're
interested. Do you know what that is,
Jacob?
That is when a woman looks at you
and glances for
a little bit
too long. You know like
you catch someone's eye across the room
and they hold the eye contact for a little
bit too long. They're flirting.
Back in the day, a woman used to drop her
handkerchief.
So let's say a lady found you.
It would be very uncouth for a woman to
ask a man out.
So what a woman would do
is drop her handkerchief.
The man would pick it up,
and it would spark conversation.
Now, what happening is here is they
are dropping their handkerchief,
but how will
you react? This is the question.
But yeah, I would just say
you want to know the price,
but you probably want to know everything
else.
So just say, "What
is it you need help with?
I'll tell you how much it'll cost."
Because if they're like, "Oh,
I never go to the
gym, I'm not accountable." You go, "Look,
you're probably looking at three
30-minute sessions a week where I need to
make sure you come to the gym." But
someone else might say, "Look,
I'm self-sufficient.
I know what I'm doing.
I just need a program." It's going to be
something different.
Liam, "Does more qualifications,
better CV equal more clients?" No.
I only have my level three PT. That's it.
Three books, several big businesses.
I've got a foundation degree in sports
coaching, but that was just at
college.
No, mate. No. Do you know what?
There's someone I really like online,
and she's doing like a PhD,
and she's about to submit it.
She's like probably in her 30s, right?
I don't even know what you have to do for
a PhD, but she said it was five years in
the working. And I was like,
"You've been working on something for five
years, and you're only going to get a
few letters on your name.
Are you mental?" Like, if
I work on something for five years,
I want a fucking six-bedroom house
and another
Porsche. You know what I mean?
Sounds crazy.
This business
is 11 months old,
and
it's done well.
And I've got no qualifications.
All I've done is go in on it.
Even this YouTube is at 14,000
subscribers.
I've only been going hard on it for like
three, four months.
I'm going to get another one of these from
this channel, and I reckon I can get it
in the next six months. So like
when people are like doing these
qualifications,
kinesiology, PhD, all of this.
If you're going to be a doctor, cool.
But if you're an online fucking coach,
why are you giving money to
something... Sure, upskill, all of that.
But I'm like,
no one gives a fuck.
No one's ever given a fuck.
Any of you gone, "James, what
are your qualifications for teaching
this?" No,
you don't care.
Because instead of wasting my time doing a
PhD, I was learning what
works, brother. Learning what works.
"When it comes to YouTube content,
is it worth sharing both longs
and shorts on the
same account?
Would it dilute the audience?" So shorts
on YouTube are on a separate
algorithm. So what I mean by that is,
if you were to get loads of viral shorts
on YouTube, it doesn't mean your longs are
going to get shown to people
and vice versa.
Two different algorithms.
Okay. "Going to get the Sony ZV-E10
and Sigma lens for content creation.
The 30 millimeter..." Okay,
the 16 mil's good for shots like this,
but great.
"I'm moving to Australia from New Zealand
this week wanting to connect with an
accountant to help run the money side of
things.
Any recommendations?" Just Google
something. I'm sure anyone will tell you.
The Sony ZV-E10 or DJI Osmo3?
The Osmo3 I think is more versatile
and better.
"Biggest lessons since becoming a dad?"
There is something more important than
work. "I know you mentioned this before.
How often do you recycle an old video?"
Depends on the growth that you're
experiencing. But you, Brent,
you need to be just pumping it.
It'd be fine.
"You going to shave your head
and start using minoxidil?"
Not really. I might shave my head,
but the fact of like
having to use something to get my hair to
grow, like look, if nature
wants it to grow, that's fine.
And guess what?
I'll be bald in a Porsche 911 GT3. Fine.
Not a problem.
Okay.
"In case in my question about physical
products like chocolates." Okay, if
you're going to sell chocolates or coffee,
this is my simple question.
Why should I use your product versus
someone else's?
"Do you invest in crypto? If yes, what
are your main holdings?" No, and I'll tell
you why. I think Bitcoin's great.
I think crypto is the future, but
it just seems like a massive distraction.
And I had a videographer,
and I had to let him go because he
was fucking obsessed
with crypto,
and he'd be lecturing me about crypto all
the time.
I said, "Look, mate, here's $1,000,
invest it for me."
And every day I'd look in my
Phantom wallet, it would go up,
it'd go down.
I was like, "This is volatile
and this just isn't good for my mental
health." And
like the last few years,
he's shoving off
that he's made like $35,000 in crypto.
And I said to him, "Okay, cool."
He's like a crypto whiz, whatever.
I sent him a screenshot of my Stripe
account.
I was like, "Mate, here's seven figures
I've made in the same time
that you've made 30K,
and you've been investing into crypto
and obsessing over it.
I've been investing into personal brand."
Now, these are both digital assets,
okay? These are both digital things
that you can invest in,
okay? Now,
instead of me looking at Solana
and Ethereum and Bitcoin
and looking at what's going to move,
the things that I care about
are social media posts and each one of
those assets that I can float,
not on the blockchain,
but on the internet, and they
can pay me dividends based on their
performances.
Now, the biggest issue here is
social media assets, videos,
even this video, I can influence.
It's very difficult to influence crypto
without pumping and dumping.
And
it's one of those things where I'm just
like
Focusing on crypto would make me poorer at
this stage of my life.
And for so many of you, I think that
if you're obsessive of crypto, this is the
biggest issue.
If you truly believe that your coins
are going to pump and make you millions,
that
is going to have a negative effect on your
life today.
Because I do not have an insurance policy,
I do not have Bitcoin that I'm holding
that's going to go to the moon.
If I don't make shit work today,
this week, this
month, and this year,
I've got to sell the house.
So,
I think the majority of people
that focus on crypto
are going to go broke from it.
Not just from the coin,
but from your mindset.
If you're waiting for an external factor
to go to the moon for you to have the
life you want,
you're fucked to begin with.
And a mate of mine, not a mate of mine,
we don't get on.
A guy I used to live with, he
was a stripper and he
was a personal trainer.
And I said to him:
"You need to quit stripping." He goes:
"Why?" I said: "You make
so much money at the weekend,
you're never going to be a great personal
trainer."
He goes: "Why?" I said:
"'Cause you don't need to."
And if you don't need what you have now to
work,
it's just not going to work.
So yeah.
"Any tips for a new PT in the UK?
I've been posting content
but got no clients."
It's because you think in your head,
stage one, stage four, stage one,
stage four.
You don't know the stages between it.
I would say check out the mentorship.
Right.
My missus is WhatsApping me saying
that I need to take the baby,
so I'm going to
rizz through these as quick as I can.
"James, love your content.
If you're successful one-to-one online
clients and
you're charging quite a lot
and fully booked,
what's the next step?" Put your
prices up.
You're fully booked,
it means you're too cheap.
And if you weren't too cheap,
you wouldn't be fully booked.
Okay. Thank you for the give free.
[mumbling] Join the mentorship.
It's my goal right now.
It's only £999 at the moment.
"Does the email course you run teach you
how to create good emails that people want
to read?" It does, yes.
And I think there's 20% off the email
advantage as well.
"What AI tools do you use day to day?"
I've started using ChatGPT quite a lot.
"Since I read 'Not a Life Coach,' I've
bought rollerblades." Cool.
[chuckles] "Hi, mate.
Is your mentorship suitable for those
starting out fresh as a
PT online coach?" Yes. Well, ultimately,
what are you going to do?
Guess for two years and then join?
It's there, mate, and it's only
going to save you time.
Nothing like this was there when I
was there.
"What's better to post on generally,
Instagram Reels or YouTube long form?"
It's for you to find out
and work backwards.
It's only through doing loads of work
there are you really going to know.
"Thoughts on overanalyzing the data on
landing pages and product examples for
clicks and actions." Basically,
the only reason you need to look at
analytics on a
landing page is to see
if you have a conversion problem
or a traffic problem.
That's it.
"Any tips on a creator getting started?"
I've done videos on this on this channel.
You got people charging 10K for business
coaching to tell people to go DM.
It's fucked.
Okay. "Not fitness related,
but advocate the course and
content." Thank you very much.
Okay. "Work in a gym in the UK.
Work 16 hours a week.
Get paid for my hours.
I pay £75 a month. Have around 15 clients.
Want to go fully online.
What should I do?" Join the course.
"Jumped on the mentorship.
Smashed through the first two modules.
This may come up later.
Which website system do you recommend for
a landing page?"
Leadpages. I love Leadpages.
"Is it cheap?" No, it's good though.
It is good. And mate, if your name
is Mark, you are probably a man.
And if you're probably a man,
your design skills are awful.
I've never seen... Women. No,
I'm not being sexist.
99% of the time you cannot leave a man
in charge of making the bed. You can't.
Men do not know what pillows
or an Egyptian or what.
They just don't know.
In the same way,
men should not be left to pick the color
palettes for a landing
page.
So for that reason, use Leadpages.
"I wonder if fitness businesses can
continue to be profitable.
Seems like it's getting oversaturated."
They said this 10 years ago, mate.
They said this 10 years ago. 2014,
the exact same thing.
You're just looking for an excuse not to
dive fully in.
And also,
even with Ozempic making people less fat,
people still need a training
program. Mate,
I still pay someone to write my training
program.
"When creating content,
how do you decide if it's good enough to
post?" You don't.
You just post it and you course correct as
time goes on.
All right. I'm afraid that there
are too many questions here, and I can
only apologize that I'm going to have to
miss some because my baby child
son is screaming upstairs.
Thank you very much for tuning in.
I will come on again soon.
I'm going to post the link here again.
My business mentorship
is currently 50% off, which
is a fucking steal for what you
get.
I'd love to see you in there.
We're going to keep it live for a few more
days.
Thank you so much for tuning in.
Really appreciate this. If you
are enjoying the content on the channel,
yeah, it's great. Thank you very much.
I will see you guys soon.
We'll do another live stream as soon as I
can. Bye.